<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../src-generated/schemas/fhir-single.xsd">
	<a name="scope"> </a>
	<h3>Introduction</h3>
	<p>PQ/CMC is a term used to describe manufacturing and testing data of pharmaceutical products. PQ/CMC encompasses topics such as drug stability, quality specification, and batch analysis, which are important aspects of drug development. PQ/CMC plays an integral part in the regulatory review process and life cycle management of pharmaceutical products. The standardization of PQ/CMC data elements and terminologies will facilitate the Agency's transition to an electronic review environment.</p>
	<p>As part of an effort intended to support future electronic acquisition and use of submitted information, a project was undertaken to identify and prioritize pharmaceutical quality/chemistry, manufacturing and controls (PQ/CMC) information that would benefit from a structured submission approach. This information would be submitted in the Common Technical Document as defined by the International Council for 
Harmonisation’s (ICH) Common Technical Document (CTD).</p>
	<p>The goals of this project  (a) to identify types of PQ/CMC information that are available in applications, information that is important to evaluate an application, information categories and elements that are common across the various application types, and (b) to provide recommendations for standardization of the categories and data types necessary for application review. This initiative will align, where comparable elements exist, with substance and product identifiers described by the International Organization of Standardization for the Identification of Medicinal Products (ISO IDMP) standards. </p>
	<p>For consistency of product quality data across FDA centers, the draft standardized data elements and terminologies were created by an Agency workgroup comprised of Subject Matter Experts (SMEs) from the Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER), the Center for Veterinary Medicine (CVM), and the Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research (CBER). Please note that data element definitions provided here have been developed for purposes of review of information in Module 3 of the eCTD.</p>
	<p>NOTE: The PQ/CMC Data Standards and Terminologies were published for public comment as part of a  in July 2017 .  The industry submitted over 450 detailed comments to all aspects of the CMC meta data standards and overwhelmingly supported the structuring and standardization of CMC data in eCTD Module 3.  </p>
</div>
